<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-02T10:14:16-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/feed.xml</id><title type="html">APCSP</title><subtitle>AP Computer Science Principles with support for Jupyter Notebooks.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">College Board Create Performance Task</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/units/2022/06/30/creatept.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="College Board Create Performance Task" /><published>2022-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/units/2022/06/30/creatept</id><author><name></name></author><category term="units" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Create Performance Task, 30% of grade on AP exam Each time we engage in Code/Code/Coding it is an opportunity to think of the possibility of fulfilling the Create Performance Task requirement. But, this is a student project and responsibility is on you. To be thinking and preparing is a mindset, one that Del Norte CompSci Teachers advise as we proceed through topics. Thus, we are getting and early start by using this Pair Share project as an iteration through the entire process, as that is the foundational principle behind PBL.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creative Development Sprint</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/30/Tri1-creative.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative Development Sprint" /><published>2022-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/30/Tri1-creative</id><author><name></name></author><category term="tri1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Creative Development - Week 3 In the Student handout… College Board states that Students need to obtain knowledge and skills that can include, but need not be limited to, “the iterative development process, strategies for collaboration, the development of both data and procedural abstractions, and describing an algorithm’s purpose and explaining how it functions. A development process includes ideation, research, reflection, design, implementation, and testing your program. Scrum Board planning, revising plans, incremental goals, and iterative development are proven methods toward achieving a successful delivery. Pair Share team needs to work together to optimize delivery to Teacher. Each student needs to become competent in HTML fragments, Jupyter Notebooks, and Python. Each student needs to begin technical application of College Board requirements in “Unt 2: Data” and “Unit 3: Algorithms and Programming”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lists, Dictionaries, Iteration</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/units/2022/06/29/lists.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lists, Dictionaries, Iteration" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/units/2022/06/29/lists</id><author><name></name></author><category term="units" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction to Python Sprint</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/29/Tri1-python.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Python Sprint" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/29/Tri1-python</id><author><name></name></author><category term="tri1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to Python - Week 1 Introduction to Python sprint is a time to learn and obtain basic skills needed to Code a little bit. Learning basics of Python Capturing notes and coding while building a Fastpages/GitHub pages and a yearlong individual notebook Establish positive PBL habits: a focused mindset in the classroom, establishing work habits to achieve success.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Abstraction Sprint</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/29/Tri1-dataabstract.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Abstraction Sprint" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/29/Tri1-dataabstract</id><author><name></name></author><category term="tri1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data Abstraction - Week 2 As you use Python, as with all programming languages, managing data is a key skill. Data abstraction is the reduction of a particular body of data to a simplified representation of the whole. Or in other words, something that is easier for the developer to understand. Data Abstraction ,along with Procedural Abstraction, are the keys making successful programs. Data Abstraction is vital when sharing data amongst developers, sharing data across the internet, or working in technologies like BioMed, Data Science, etc. Variables are a way to name, store, data and reference data. We have started working with variables in our last sprint. Lists and Dictionaries are variables with extended features for storing and retrieving data. Lists, think of [] square brackets, are a way of grouping data in an ordered sequence, and will be a big part of the requirement for the College Board Create Task project. All students will need to become proficient in lists to do well in the class and succeed in the AP exam. Dictionaries, think of {} curly braces, are a way of grouping data into in key-value relationships. Dictionaries are similar to JavaScript Object Notation (JSON). Knowledge of Dictionaries and JSON is key to Web Development.]]></summary></entry></feed>