<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-29T21:46:38-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/feed.xml</id><title type="html">APCSP</title><subtitle>AP Computer Science Principles with support for Jupyter Notebooks.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Python, Lists, Dictionaries</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/units/2022/06/29/lists.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Python, Lists, Dictionaries" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/units/2022/06/29/lists</id><author><name></name></author><category term="units" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction to Python Sprint</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/29/Tri1-python.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Python Sprint" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/29/Tri1-python</id><author><name></name></author><category term="tri1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to Python - Week 1 Introduction to Python sprint is a time to learn and obtain basic skills needed to Code a little bit. Learning basics of Python Capturing notes and coding while building a Fastpages/GitHub pages and a yearlong individual notebook Establish positive PBL habits: a focused mindset in the classroom, establishing work habits to achieve success.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Abstraction Sprint</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/29/Tri1-dataabstract.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Abstraction Sprint" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/29/Tri1-dataabstract</id><author><name></name></author><category term="tri1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data Abstraction - Week 2 As you use Python, as with all programming languages, managing data is a key skill. Data abstraction is the reduction of a particular body of data to a simplified representation of the whole. Or in other words, something that is easier for the developer to understand. Data Abstraction ,along with Procedural Abstraction, are the keys making successful programs. Data Abstraction is vital when sharing data amongst developers, sharing data across the internet, or working in technologies like BioMed, Data Science, etc. Variables are a way to name, store, data and reference data. We have started working with variables in our last sprint. Lists and Dictionaries are variables with extended features for storing and retrieving data. Lists, think of [] square brackets, are a way of grouping data and will be a big part of the requirement for the College Board Create Task project. All students will need to become proficient in lists to do well in the class and succeed in the AP exam. Dictionaries, think of {} curly braces, are a way of grouping data into in key-value relationships. Dictionaries are similar to JavaScript Object Notation (JSON). Knowledge of Dictionaries and JSON is key to Web Development.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tool Setup Sprint - Tools and Pair Programming</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/27/Tri1-setup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tool Setup Sprint - Tools and Pair Programming" /><published>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/27/Tri1-setup</id><author><name></name></author><category term="tri1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AP CSP COURSE OUTLINE Methodology. Project Based Learning (PBL) Guideline. The 5 Big Ideas AP Computer Science Principles Key Learnings for 2022-2023 Collaboratively Build, Deploy and Host Web Pages Programming, Algorithms, APIs, and Databases Team and Individual Project will highlight all 5 Big Units, either academically or in interest fashion Establish “Real World” Scrum Team projects Preference is to establish projects with a Customer/Sponsor, including me or other Teachers and Admin on campus. We have some projects that have been started by other student groups that can be extended. Projects will be tracked using GitHub README (Time Boxing Events), Issues and Projects tools Create “GitHub Pages” Individual postings and notebooks Build individual GitHub Pages Web Site to _post Notes and Learnings AP create task project and testing in May]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TT 1.1.0 Focus and Habits - Yale Professor on Successful People</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT131-focus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TT 1.1.0 Focus and Habits - Yale Professor on Successful People" /><published>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT131-focus</id><author><name></name></author><category term="techtalk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Psychology and the Good Life, by Laurie Santos This video is very relevant to students. Laurie Santos is a professor at Yale has produced one of the most popular classes of all time at Yale (1 of 4 students take this class).]]></summary></entry></feed>