<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-28T22:05:01-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/feed.xml</id><title type="html">APCSP</title><subtitle>AP Computer Science Principles with support for Jupyter Notebooks.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">TT 1.0.0 - Tools and Equipment</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT100-tools.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TT 1.0.0 - Tools and Equipment" /><published>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT100-tools</id><author><name></name></author><category term="techtalk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tools and Equipment make Development Easy Learning Development tools, working with Projects, is the key to a rapid entry into Code/Code/Coding. A Computer, Git, and an Code Editor are the starting points for coding. Computers using either MacOS, Windows, or Linux are requirements for the course. GitHub, is Git hosted in the Cloud. It is the defacto hosting platform for version control and collaboration. It lets you and others work together on projects from anywhere in the world. Think of it as the Google Docs for Coders. Version Control is the task of keeping a software system of many versions and configurations well organized. Version Control History of files and changes in Version Control System (ie GitHub) is very important! Ultimately, any Coder will break things or delete things! Looking at older versions and configurations at a microscopic detail is sometimes the only way to unwind bugs. Visual Studio Code (abbreviations VS Code, VSCode or VSC) is a powerful Code Editor. VSCode performs a lot of magic and automation behind the scenes to make your Code/Code/Coding life easier. There is a back-in-the-day story hear, but short version is VSCode qualifies, IMO, to be called and Integrated Development Environment (IDE). It allows you to Edit files, Build your Code, and Pull/Push Code from and to the GitHub. FYI, VSCode is new to APCS this year, former IDE’s used in CompSci classes include XCode, Eclipse, and IntelliJ. Jupyter Documents (.ipynb) is a document format for creating and sharing computational documents. These documents allow you to compute segments of Python or Java code as you are taking notes. These are new to AP CS this year, but are viewed as very powerful in gaining a quick understanding of coding concepts. Jupyter documents are often called “notebooks”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TT 1.1.1 Fastpages - Tour of GH Pages / Fastpages</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT120-fastpages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TT 1.1.1 Fastpages - Tour of GH Pages / Fastpages" /><published>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT120-fastpages</id><author><name></name></author><category term="techtalk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tour of Fastpages]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TT 1.0.1 Roles, Agile, Issues, and Scrum Board</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT130-roles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TT 1.0.1 Roles, Agile, Issues, and Scrum Board" /><published>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT130-roles</id><author><name></name></author><category term="techtalk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Agile Methodology]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TT 1.1.0 Focus and Habits - Yale Professor on Successful People</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT131-focus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TT 1.1.0 Focus and Habits - Yale Professor on Successful People" /><published>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/techtalk/2022/06/27/TT131-focus</id><author><name></name></author><category term="techtalk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Psychology and the Good Life, by Laurie Santos This video is very relevant to students. Laurie Santos is a professor at Yale has produced one of the most popular classes of all time at Yale (1 of 4 students take this class).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tool Setup Sprint - Tools and Pair Programming</title><link href="https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/27/Tri1-introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tool Setup Sprint - Tools and Pair Programming" /><published>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://nighthawkcoders.github.io/APCSP/tri1/2022/06/27/Tri1-introduction</id><author><name></name></author><category term="tri1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AP CSP COURSE OUTLINE Methodology. Project Based Learning (PBL) Guideline. The 5 Big Ideas AP Computer Science Principles Key Learnings for 2022-2023 Collaboratively Build, Deploy and Host Web Pages Programming, Algorithms, APIs, and Databases Team and Individual Project will highlight all 5 Big Units, either academically or in interest fashion Establish “Real World” Scrum Team projects Preference is to establish projects with a Customer/Sponsor, including me or other Teachers and Admin on campus. We have some projects that have been started by other student groups that can be extended. Projects will be tracked using GitHub README (Time Boxing Events), Issues and Projects tools Create “GitHub Pages” Individual postings and notebooks Build individual GitHub Pages Web Site to _post Notes and Learnings AP create task project and testing in May]]></summary></entry></feed>